Inventory of the Walter B. Snook collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Walter B. Snook collection
1914-1945
67024
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
The collection is comprised of photographs of military operations in France during World War I, and reports, surrender instructions, and military newspaper issues, relating to military operations in the Pacific Theater during World War II. Includes a copy of a telegram from Admiral Chester W. Nimitz on the capture of Iwo Jima, and a proclamation to the people of the Volcano Islands.
Snook, Walter B., collector.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1967.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical note
circa 1898 Born
circa 1917 Volunteers with American Expeditionary Forces, Air Services
1920 Graduates from Stanford University
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection is comprised of photographs of military operations in France during World War I, and reports, surrender instructions, and military newspaper issues, relating to military operations in the Pacific Theater during World War II. Includes a copy of a telegram from Admiral Chester W. Nimitz on the capture of Iwo Jima, and a proclamation to the people of the Volcano Islands.
Nimitz, Chester W., 1885-1966.; Iwo Jima, Battle of, 1945.; World War, 1914-1918--Pictorial works.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Pacific Ocean.
- Photographs, circa 1914-1918
  - Aerial views of airplane hangers (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Airplanes (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Ambulance corps volunteers, field hospital, ambulances, burial, wounded (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Automobile (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Battlefield artillery (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Bunkers and barracks (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Destruction in France's rural areas (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Destruction in France's urban areas (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Military troops in France (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Photo tours, France (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Pilots with their airplanes (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Ship views en route to France (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Stanford University ambulance unit, first (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Stanford University versus French troops football game (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Two Russian soldiers (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - DVD containing digital copies of World War I photographs (Box-folder 1: 16)
- Proclamation to the people of Volcano Islands by Admiral Nimitz, 1945 March 14 (Box-folder 1: 17)
- United States Naval Communication Service, Iwo Jima, 1945 March 16 (Box-folder 1: 18)
- Copy of telegram from Admiral Nimitz on the capture of Iwo Jima, 1945 March 17 (Box-folder 1: 19)
- Surrender instructions, 1945 March 18 (Box-folder 1: 20)
- Periodic reports and other documents, 1944 September (Box-folder 1: 21)
- Newsletters, circa 1945 (Box-folder 1: 22)
- Declassified U.S. government records, 1945 (Box-folder 1: 23)
  Scope and Contents note
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, relased in full or in part. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover.
  - 2015 May release of records, 1945
    Includes an intelligence bulletin, 8 June 1945, translating a document from a Japanese prisoner captured on Iwo Jima; May 1945 reports about enemy activity on Iwo Jima; and a memo, 18 March 1945, regarding the capture of Iwo Jima.